Some scientists insist that once we discover the truth about the world, we are done.
一些科学家坚称，一旦我们发现了关于世界的真理，就大功告成了。
Anyone who denies such truths, they suggest, is stupid or ignorant.
他们认为，任何否认这些真理的人，不是愚蠢就是无知。
Well, no.
嗯，并非如此。
In science, what we do is both hard and, often, hard to explain.
在科学领域，我们所做的事既艰难，又往往难以解释。
The history of science offers many examples of matters that scientists thought they had resolved, only to discover that these matters needed to be reconsidered.
科学史上有许多这样的例子：科学家们以为某些问题已经解决，结果却发现这些问题需要重新考虑。
Familiar examples include Earth as the center of the universe and the stability of continents.
大家熟悉的例子有“地球是宇宙的中心”和“大陆稳定不动”。
Science is a process of learning and discovery, and sometimes we learn that what we thought was right is wrong.
科学是一个学习和发现的过程，有时我们会认识到，我们原以为正确的东西其实是错的。
To say that science is “true” or “permanent” is like saying that “beauty is absolute.”
说科学是“正确的”或“永恒的”，就好比说“美是绝对的”。
At best, it’s a bit off-key.
这种说法往好里说，也有点不恰当。
The concept of beauty today is very different from what it was in ancient Greece or the Middle Ages, and so are most of our “laws” of nature.
如今美的概念与古希腊或中世纪时大不相同，我们的大多数自然“法则”也是如此。
Other scientists may say scientific findings are true because they use “the scientific method.”
另一些科学家可能会说，科学发现之所以正确，是因为采用了“科学方法”。
But we can never actually agree on what that method is.
但对于这种方法究竟是什么，我们实际上永远无法达成一致。
Some will say it is observation and description of the world.
有人会说，科学方法就是观察和描述世界。
Others will say it is the use of experience and experiment.
另一些人会说，科学方法就是运用经验和实验。
Recently a leading scientist said the scientific method was to avoid fooling oneself into thinking something is true that is not.
最近，一位顶尖科学家说，科学方法就是避免自己骗自己，把并不正确的东西误当成正确的。
Each of these views has its value, but if the claim is that any one of these is the scientific method, then they all fail.
这些观点各有其价值，但如果声称其中任何一种就是唯一的科学方法，那么它们全都站不住脚。
History and philosophy have shown that the idea of a singular scientific method is unscientific.
历史和哲学已经表明，认为存在唯一一种科学方法的观念是不科学的。
In fact, the methods of science have varied between disciplines and across time.
事实上，科学方法一直因学科而异，也随时代而变。
Scientists have bitterly argued about which methods are the best, and, as we all know, bitter arguments rarely get resolved.
科学家们一直在激烈争论哪些方法最好，而众所周知，激烈的争论很少能得到解决。
In my view, science is not simple, and neither is the natural world.
在我看来，科学并不简单，自然界也不简单。
Our efforts to understand and explain the natural world are just that: efforts.
我们为理解和解释自然界所做的努力，也不过是努力而已。
Because we’re human, we often fall flat.
因为我们是人，所以常常会失败。
The good news is that when that happens, we pick ourselves up, brush ourselves off, and get back to work.
好消息是，发生这种情况时，我们会爬起来，掸掉身上的灰尘，重新投入工作。
Understanding the world we live in, and using that knowledge to do useful things, is its own reward.
理解我们生活的世界，并运用这些知识去做有用的事，这本身就是一种回报。